Inventory of the Frank H. Allyn papers, 1846-1968
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Frank H. Allyn papers
1846-1968
Allyn, Frank H., 1875-1957.
05912
circa 3 cubic feet.
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Biography of Frank H. Allyn
Frank H. Allyn was the first engineering graduate of the University of Wyoming, a draftsman in the U.S. Surveyor General's office in Cheyenne, an early homesteader of the Riverton Valley, and postmaster of Riverton, Wyoming, from 1907 to 1914. He retired from the Wyoming State Highway Department in 1949, having worked in its drafting office since 1920.
Scope and Content
The collection contains primarily maps, many by Frank H. Allyn, including Wyoming highway maps (1930-1968), lands of Union Pacific Railroad Co., road logs from the Laramie, Cheyenne and Rawlins areas (1920-1923), Shoshone and other Indian lands, school districts in Wyoming (1910), and maps of the Riverton and Fremont County area including the original plat of Riverton by F.H. Allyn (1906).
Also included are maps of oil fields and copies of historical maps such as the trail from Missouri to Oregon (1846), routes from Ft. Laramie to Great Salt Lake (1858), and Territory of Wyoming (1876). Some biographical and personal material is also included.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions on the materials for research purposes, and the collection is open to the public.
Related Materials
There are no known other archival collections created by Frank H. Allyn at the date of processing.
Acquisition Information
The collection was received from Frank H. Allyn in 1950 and from Laura Allyn Ekstrom in 1975.
Access Terms
Wyoming. State Highway Dept.; Laramie Rolling Mills.; Union Pacific Railroad Company.; Oil fields -- Wyoming.; Roads -- Wyoming.; School districts -- Wyoming.; Cartography -- Wyoming.; Roads -- Wyoming -- Maps.; Wyoming -- Maps.; Wind River Indian Reservation (Wyo.); Riverton (Wyo.); Fremont County (Wyo.); Wyoming -- History -- 1890-1918.; Wyoming -- History -- 1919-1945.; Wyoming -- History -- 1946-; Maps.; Cartographers.
Places; Wyoming; People, Ethnicity, and Culture; Native Americans; Education; Elementary and Secondary Education; Business, Industry, Labor, and Commerce; Transportation; Science, Technology and Health; Energy Production
Container List
- Maps:
  - Maps: Map of Pavilion in Fremont County, October 14, 1908 (Box 2)
  - Map: Original Plat of Riverton Wyoming by Frank H. Allyn, Blue Prints and Van Dyke, Copy of Joyne Drummonas map and original draft of his certification and letter by W.S. Adams, October 14, 1908 (Box 2)
  - Map: large Cheyenne, Wyoming Map (Box 2)
  - Map: State of Colorado Map, 1897 (Box 2)
  - Map: State of Wyoming Map, 2 copies (Box 2)
  - Map: State of Montana Map, 1897 (Box 2)
  - Map: State of Utah Map, 1902 (Box 2)
  - Map: State of Idaho, 1899 (Box 2)
  - Map: Lands of Union Pacific Railroad Company in Southeastern Wyoming and Northern Colorado, 1904 (Box 3)
  - Map: Wind River Indian Reservatoin, 2 copies (Box 3)
  - Map: Territory of Wyoming, 2 Positive Photostats and 1 Negative, 1876 (Box 3)
  - Map: State of Wyoming Condition Map, by Frank H. Allyn, June 1, 1926 (Box 2)
  - Riverton Wyoming-Fremont County and its suburbs, T.I.N.R. 43 of the W.R.M., Blue Print and White Print (Box 2)
  - Union Pacific Railroad, Lincoln County, Nebraska, Blue Print and accompanying sheet, January 15, 1906 corrected to January 27, 1905 (Box 1)
  - Union Pacific Railroad Solon, Carbon County, Wyoming, Blueprint with accompanying sheet, January 15, 1906 corrected to April 12, 1905 (Box 1)
  - Fremont County, Wyoming-S.E. 1/4 Sec. 23, T.I.N., R. 4E, W.R.M (Box 3)
  - Preliminary Map Ft. Kearney South Pass and Honey Lake Wagon Road, Photostat, 1857-1858 (Box 1)
  - Map of Hudson Wyoming, I. D. Woodward, 1911 (Box 2)
  - Wyoming Highway Map by F.H. Allyn, Blueprint and Whiteprint, 1928 (Box 2)
  - Wyoming State Highway Map made from above map (Box 2)
  - Trails of the Old West by William H. Jackson (Box 2)
  - Trackage at Riverton, Wyoming Refining Company, Blueprint, July 16, 1919 (Box 2)
  - Holt's New Map of Wyoming before Wyoming became a state, Van Dyke, 1885 (Box 2)
  - Plans showing Uncle Sam and Copper King Group of Lode Claims, February 6, 1907 (Box 2)
  - Map of Converse County, September, 1936 (Box 1)
  - Map of Campbell County, September, 1936 (Box 1)
  - Map of Natrona County, August, 1936 (Box 1)
  - Sketch exhibiting routes between Fort Laramie and Great Salt Lake, Photostatic copy, January, 1858 (Box 3)
  - High Line & Low Line Canal, Pavilion Area, Fremont County (Box 2)
  - Maps of Yellowstone and Missouri Rivers and their Tributaries, Photostatic copy, 1859-1860 (Box 3)
  - Town of Riverton In Fremont County, Blueprint and Original Drawing, 1906 (Box 3)
  - State of Wyoming Highway Department-Cheyenne Condition Map, 10 copies (Box 2)
  - Map of Cheyenne and Adjacent subdivisons, Photostatic copy, 1911 (Box 2)
  - Map of Pavillion-Fremont County, Wyoming by Frank H. Allyn, Whiteprint and 3 Van Dykes, 1919 (Box 2)
  - Map of Wyoming, 5 copies (Box 2)
  - Map of proposed Pipe Line of the Maverick Springs Pipe Line Compnay, Fremont County, August, 1933 (Box 2)
  - Tracing of 1/4 section by F.H. Allyn (Box 1)
  - Shoshone Irrigation Project, Wyoming-Montana, 1938 (Box 2)
  - Ground Plan of the Laramie Rolling Mills, F.H. Allyn, Blueprint, 1897 (Box 2)
  - Map-Cheno Oil Company Field (Box 2)
  - Map-Selish Oil Company, Missoula, Montana (Box 3)
  - Map-Allies Oil Company, Riverton, Wyoming (Box 3)
  - Map-Fremont County Wyoming Oil Fields (Box 3)
  - Arlington-Riverton Oil Company (Box 2)
  - Shoshoni Ditch Blueprint (Box 2)
  - Map-Riverton, Wyoming Original Tracing and Blueprint by Frank H. Allyn, 1906 (Box 3)
  - Laramie County, Wyoming-State Highway Department Map, 1936 revised 1937 to 1939 (Box 3)
  - Plat showing lands enclosed by A.W. Bristol, Blueprint (Box 2)
  - Plat of the Ceded area Shoshone or Wind River Indian Reservation, August 15, 1906 (Box unknown)
  - State of Wyoming Highway Department Map showing state Highway systems and status of improvements, 3 copies, December 31, 1926 (Box 2)
  - Lode Claims, Shoshone Mining and Milling Company, 4 Tracings by F. H. Allyn (Box 3)
  - Plat of the Townsite of Wahaba, 3 Blueprints and 1 Tracing (Box 2)
  - Stock Growers National Bank-Map of Wyoming Counties, 1904 (Box 2)
  - State of Wyoming Highway Department-Cheyenne Condition Map, June 1, 1936 (Box 3)
  - Map-Laramie County, Wyoming, 1940 (Box 2)
  - Map of Cheyenne, Wyoming, 6 sections (Box 1)
  - Guide to Black Hills and Goldfields of Northwest (Box 2)
  - Medicine Bow National Forest Maps, 5 sections, 1937 (Box unknown)
  - Cheyenne and Adjacent Suburbs, by W.K. Jones, 1919 (Box unknown)
  - Wyoming State Map by F.H. Allyn, 4 Blueprints, 1930 (Box unknown)
  - Riverton Map, 1919 (Box unknown)
  - Riverton and Suburbs and Wyoming Tie and Timber Company (Box unknown)
  - Proposed sewer at Riverton, July 6, 1916 (Box unknown)
  - Riverton Water Works and Sewer System, 1916 (Box unknown)
  - Map and Directory of Riverton, 1911 (Box unknown)
  - Riverton and Suburbs by F.H. Allyn (Box unknown)
  - Berle 1st Addition to Riverton, 2 copies (Box unknown)
  - Burch's 1st Addition to original I.D. Woodward Map (Box unknown)
  - Riverton, Wyoming Additons and Subdivisions, 2 sets, 1919-1921 (Box unknown)
  - United States including Territories and Insular Possessions, 1953 (Box unknown)
  - Riverton, Wyoming with subdivisions by F.H. Allyn, 4 Blueprints, 1 Van Dyke (Box unknown)
  - U-WYO Oil Company Riverton, Wyoming (Box 3)
  - Kinniar Territorial Ditch, April, 1909 (Box 1)
  - Riverton, Wyoming and suburbs, Blueprint, 1915 (Box unknown)
  - Carbon County, Wyoming, 2 Sections, 1935 (Box unknown)
  - Albany County, Wyoming, 1935 (Box unknown)
  - Original Tracing, Riverton, Wyoming by F.H Allyn, Van Dyke, Riverton, Similar to one above but not from this tracing, 1918 (Box unknown)
  - Oil Map-Cheno and other oil holdings, 3 Van Dyke Negatives (Box unknown)
  - Map of Wyoming with Governers, 1st through 16th (Box unknown)
  - Map of the United States (Box unknown)
  - Map of the World (Box unknown)
  - Map of the Panama Canal and surrounding territory with presidents of U.S from 1st to 27th, also rulers of the world (Box unknown)
  - Big Sand Oil Field by F.H Allyn, Van Dyke, 1917 (Box unknown)
  - Cheno Oil Company, Riverton, Wyoming and Area, Van Dykes, 1917-1918 (Box unknown)
  - Wyoming and Northwestern Railway Proposed Tie Treating Yard 1.2 miles west of Riverton, Wyoming-Track to be laid May 15 and August 15, 1914, working drawing by F.H Allyn (Box unknown)
  - Lander, Wyoming, by E.W Hainsworth, Blueprint, July, 1906 (Box unknown)
  - Riverton, Wyoming-Fremont County, N.E 1/4 Sec. 34, T.I.N, R.4E., 1907 (Box unknown)
  - N.H Brown Fremont County School Districts, Van Dyke Negative, February 1915 (Box unknown)
  - Josephine A. Taylor Ditch, Rock Creek, Wyoming, 1900 (Box unknown)
  - Wind River Reservation, Wyoming (Box unknown)
  - Laramie County-Comprising other counties, 3 copies, 1904 (Box unknown)
  - Map of that part of the Wind River or Shoshone Indian Reservation to be opened for settlement August 15, 1906, under President's proclamation (Box unknown)
  - Map of Wind River Indian Reservation showing allotments to be sold and leased on the ceded and diminished Reservation (Box unknown)
  - Military Reservation-Ft. Bridger, 3 copies (Box 1)
  - Big and Little Wind and Popo Agie River Valleys, Fremont County, Van Dykes 3, 1910 (Box unknown)
  - Map of Riverton, Wyoming with additions and subdivisions, Blue on White, 1919 (Box unknown)
  - Laramie County, showing landowners, streams, etc., 3 sections (Box unknown)
  - Sectional Map of Wyoming, 1918 (Box unknown)
  - Riverton, Wyoming with adjoining additions and subdivisions, By F. H. Allyn, 1919 (Box 3)
  - Map by Corral Company Ditch, Fremont County by R. H. Hall, April 29, 1910 (Box 2)
  - Oil Well Field Borel No. 1 Ditch Fremont County (Box 2)
  - Oil Well Field Borel No. 2 Ditch T.4, N.R.3, Fremont County (Box 2)
  - Oil Well Field Beck Ditch, May 20, 1907 (Box 2)
  - Wyoming Territory 1883, by G. L. Holt, 2 Photostatic copies (Box 2)
  - Map of Thermopolis, East Thermopolis, and Big Horn Springs State Reserve, Photostatic copy, 1928 (Box 2)
  - Elk Migration and Management Study map of Grand Teton National Park, 6 copies (Box 2)
  - Riverton, Wyoming Irrigation Project, 1922 (Box 2)
  - Independence Rock survey, 2 black on white prints (Box 2)
  - Map of Oregon and Upper California (Box 1)
  - Topographical Map, Oregon Trail, 7 sections (Box 1)
  - Topographical Map, Road from Missouri to Oregon, 7 Photostatic copies, 1846 (Box 1)
  - U. S. Reclamation Service-Riverton Irrigation Project, 2 sections, 1922 (Box 3)
  - State of Wyoming Highway Department Condition Map, 1930 (Box 3)
  - State of Wyoming Highway Map, 1930 (Box 3)
  - State of Wyoming Highway Map, 4 copies, 1932 (Box 3)
  - State of Wyoming Highway Map, 4 copies, 1933 (Box 3)
  - State of Wyoming Highway Map, 4 copies, 1935 (Box 3)
  - State of Wyoming Highway Map, 2 copies, 1936 (Box 3)
  - State of Wyoming Highway Map, 4 copies, 1937 (Box 3)
  - State of Wyoming Highway Map, 1938 (Box 3)
  - State of Wyoming Highway Map, 1941 (Box 3)
  - State of Wyoming Highway Map, 1947 (Box 3)
  - State of Wyoming Highway Map, 1950 (Box 3)
  - State of Wyoming Highway Map, 1958 (Box 3)
- Pamphlet-Medicine Bow National Forest, 1930 (Box 3)
- Photostatic Copy of Signature for Governor Nels Smith, drawn by F. H. Allyn, 8 copies, 1942 (Box 3)
- 4 Drawings of plans for Kalaidescopes drawn by F. H. Allyn, 1940 (Box 3)
- Blueprint of "An Experienced Draftsman" cartoon plus tracing by F. H. Allyn, 1905 (Box 3)
- Scroll of Appreciation - "A Lost Chord" poem by Frank H. Allyn, 9 copies (Box 3)
- Honor Roll of the Wyoming Highway Department, World War II (Box 3)
- Union Pacific Railroad Standard Plan for Signal Maintainers House, blueprint (Box 3)
- Maps:
  - Wyoming Highway Map, 1932 (Box 3)
  - Wyoming Highway Map, 1947 (Box 3)
  - Wyoming Highway Map, 1950 (Box 3)
  - Wyoming Highway Map, 1954 (Box 3)
  - Wyoming Highway Map, 1955 (Box 3)
  - Wyoming Highway Map, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Wyoming Map, Conoco Travel Bureau, undated (Box 3)
  - Wyoming Map, California Company Road Map, 1939 (Box 3)
  - State of Wyoming Highway Department Condition Map, June 1, 1924 (Box 3)
  - Map of School Districts 13- 14- 20 - 24- 25- 26 - 29 - 30 - 32 on 1910 Map of Wyoming (Box 3)
  - Burlington Route Time Tables, January 13, 1946 (Box 3)
  - Plat of Ceded Area, Shoshone or Wind River Indian Reservation, Wyoming, 1906 (Box 3)
  - Rand McNally Vest Pocket Map of Wyoming Counties, 1900 (Box 2)
  - Clason Map of Wyoming, 1908 (Box 3)
  - Fremont County Wyoming Map, 1906 (Box 3)
  - Map of Designated Wyoming Highways, June 4, 1914 (Box 3)
  - Township Map of Shoshone Indian Reservation in Wyoming with Sectional Plat for ready use (Box 3)
- Road Logs:
  - Cheyenne To Pole Mountain Military Reservation (via the Lions Trail Cheyenne to Laramie) Wyoming, 1920 (Box 3)
  - Laramie to Encampment (Via Rocky Mountain Highway) Colorado, 2 copies, 1920 (Box 3)
  - Laramie to Pole Mountain Military Reservation (via the Lions Trail) Wyoming, 2 copies, 1920 (Box 3)
  - Laramie to Rock River, Arlington and Sand Lake (via Lincoln Highway) Wyoming, 2 Copies, 1920 (Box 3)
  - Laramie to Sand Creek and Big Laramie River, Wyoming-Colorado, 2 copies, 1920 (Box 3)
  - Dubois to Yellowstone National Park (via Rocky Mountain Highway) Wyoming, 2 copies, 1921 (Box 3)
  - Encapment to Rawlins (via Rocky Mountain Highway) and Rawlins to Medicine Bow Lodge, Wyoming, 2 copies, 1921 (Box 3)
  - Laramie to Brooklyn Lake (via New Road) Wyoming, 1921 (Box 3)
  - Rawlins to Lander (via Rocky Mountain Highway) Wyoming, 2 copies, 1921 (Box 3)
  - Laramie to Keystone, Wyoming, 2 copies, 1923 (Box 3)
- Public Sale Indian Lands, August 20, 1917 (Subject Files, Folder In2-L)
- Questions About the Riverton Project Answered (Subject Files, Folder Irr7-rip)
- Shoshone Reservation Wyoming, 2 pamphlets (Subject Files, Folder Irr7-shp)
- Account Book in Frank H. Allyn's Handwriting (Box 3)
- Map: Wyoming State Highway Map Drawn by Frank H. Allyn, 1925 (Biographical Files, Folder B-al59-fh)
- Newspaper clippings: Last Rites for Frank H. Allyn, Wyoming State Tribune, August 14, 1957 (Biographical Files, Folder B-al59-fh)
- Newspaper clippings: Mary J. Allyn Dies at 89, Wyoming State Tribune, July 12, 1965 (Biographical Files, Folder B-al59-fh)
- Newspaper Clippings: He'll Feed 1,700 Hungary Scouts Wyoming State Tribune, undated (Biographical Files, Folder B-al59-fh)
- Photographs: 1 Photograph Frank H. Allyn, 1907-1914 (Photo Files, Folder B-al59-fh)
- Photographs: 1 photograph Mr. and Mrs. Frank H. Allyn, 1907-1915 (Photo Files, Folder B-al59-fh)
- Photographs: 1 Photograph U.S. Surveyor Generals Office with Frank H. Allyn in background, 1905 (Photo Files, Folder B-al59-fh)
- Miscellaneous: 4 pieces of Letterhead-Frank H. Allyn, Blue and Black Printing (Biographical Files, Folder B-al59-fh)
- Miscellaneous: 2 Business cards-Frank H. Allyn, Blue and Black Printing (Biographical Files, Folder B-al59-fh)
- Miscellaneous: Mr. and Mrs. Frank H. Allyn, Riverton Pioneers, written by Laura Allyn Ekstrom, August 1956 (Biographical Files, Folder B-al59-fh)
- Pamphlet: Shoshone Reservation Wyoming: Greatest Irrigaion System in the County Being Built by Wyoming Centeral Irrigation Company, undated (Subject Files, Folder In2-res-wr)